PATRICK MANNING

Data Analyst

615.890.8276

<u>HCPATTY@YAHOO.COM</u>

https://github.com/ManningPatrick

linkedin.com/in/patrick-manning

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Problem-solving creative leader with professional management experience. My desire to re-train led me to the NSS Data Analytics Jumpstart class and Data Analytics Bootcamp. With a background in the restaurant industry, as well as having been a small business owner, I bring a unique perspective to data analytics.

DATA ANALYTICS EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYTICS APPRENTICE | NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | Aug 2021 - PRESENT

Nashville Software School is a nonprofit organization that prepares its students for careers in a variety of coding fields, including data analytics, through team-based, project-based learning.

PROJECTS

- City Cemetery Burial (Excel): Cleaned and explored dataset on burials at the Nashville City Cemetery from 1846 to 1979 to find interesting facts for marketing materials for the cemetery. Created visualizations on age at death by race, number of burials by year, common causes of death, and more.
- App Trader (SQL, Excel): Cleaned, explored, and analyzed data from the Apple App Store and Google Play Store. Visualized and presented data-based investment recommendations on the top 10 most profitable apps in both app stores, as well as what genres, price ranges, and content ratings of apps tend to be the most profitable.
- Clean Drinking Water (PowerBI, Excel): Cleaned and explored dataset on global drinking water tests from 2015 to 2018. Created interactive dashboard to visualize the data to compare factors such as location, number of test samples, and time of sample.

SKILLS

Excel, SQL, Python, Power BI, Tableau

WORK EXPERIENCE

Certified Trainer (CT) | Old Chicago, Murfreesboro, TN | 2016 - 2020

- Reliable cook trained in all areas of the kitchen, able to handle high volume business
- Train new employees and work with management to ensure quality and monitor food cost

Owner | The Book Corner, Murfreesboro, TN | 2011 - 2015

Owner/operator – small used bookstore

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full Time Data Analytics Bootcamp, DDA5 Expected Graduation Jan 2022